Guide to the Rice University Ad hoc and Other Committees Records UA 306
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Ad hoc and Other Committees Records
1946-1998
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 306
7 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
Minutes and notes representing the work of ad hoc and other committees at Rice University.
Biographical / Historical
Ad hoc committees at Rice University for short term processes at the university.
Scope and Contents
Minutes and notes representing the work of ad hoc and other committees at Rice University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this restricted material requires written permission from the Rice University Vice President for Admininistration Office.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This materials has been transferred from within the university over time.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
minutes (administrative records); notes; letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Ad Hoc and other committees
  - Academic Development Committee, 1961-62; 155872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Planning Committee, 1962-64; 155873 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Academic Problems, n.d.; 155874 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Accommodations and Admissions, 1963; 155875 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Addition to the Abercrombie Lab, 1968; 155876 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Committee, 1962-69; 155877 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Administrative Computer Committee, 1967-69; 155878 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - [Committee on] Administrative Computer Applications, 1969; 155879 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Admissions Procedures Committee, 1969-70; 155880 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Aeronautics and Astronautical Engineering Committee, 1964; 155881 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Alumni-Student Liaison Committee, 1970; 155882 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - [Committee on the] Applications of Mathematics, 1967; 155883 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - [Committee on] Applied Mathematics and Systems Research, 1965-68; 156056 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Related Material
    See also: [Admin. Comm. in] Systems Theory and Applied Maths., 1965 (Box 11).
  - [Committee on] Artificial Heart Project, 1964-65; 156073 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [Special Faculty Committee on the] Athletic Curriculum, 1960; 156074 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bicentennial Committee, 1975-76; 156075 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Biochemistry Program Committee, 1968; 156076 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Biomedical Engineering, 1966-67; 156077 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bio-Medical Laboratory Committee, 1967; 156078 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brown Development Committee, 1970-73; 156079 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - [Committee on] Calendar Changes; a.k.a. [Comm. on] Academic Calendar, 1963-67; 156080 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Campus Recruiting, 1970; 156081 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [Committee on] Campus Store, 1977-82; 156082 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Campus Store Board of Control, 1970-71; 156083 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - [Special Joint Faculty-Student Comm. on] Case of Joseph Neil Barfield, 1963; 156084 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Centralized Computer Policy, 1968-69; 156085 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Coed Colleges, 1973-77; 156086 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - [Committee on] Coed Housing, 1970-73; 156087 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - [Committee on] Combined Graduate and Undergraduate Studies, 1965-1967; 156088 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Commencement Speakers Committee, 1970; 156089 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Commencement Study Committee, 1969-70; 156090 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Commencement Committee, 1986; 156091 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - [Ad hoc Commission of] Curriculum Conversion, 1977; 156092 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - [Comm. on] Determine Professional Standing; a.k.a. Professional Personnel Board, 1966-67; 156093 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Development Advisory Committee, 1970-71; 156094 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - [Committee on] Development of Endowment and New Resources, 1970-72; 156109 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Disasters and Emergencies, 156110 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Education Policies for Non-Academic Employees, 1969; 156111 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Committee on] Educational Enhancement, 1975-79; 156112 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Carnegie Committee on] Educational Inquiry, 1952-56; 156113 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - [Committee on] Engineering Drawing, 1953-55; 156114 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Engineering Enrollment, 1968; 156115 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - [Committee on] Ethnic and Minority Group Studies, 1969; 156116 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - [Committee on the] Evaluation of the Undergraduate Experience, 1968-71; 156117 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - [Committee on] Exhibits, 1964-66; 156118 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - [Committee on] Extracurricular Student Study Programs, 156119 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - [Committee on] Faculty, Students and Alumni, 1962-69; 156120 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Food Service Committee, 1963; 156121 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Food Committee, 1982-85; 156122 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Forum Committee, 1961-65; 156123 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - [Committee on] Foundations, 1972-73; 156124 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - [Committee on] Freshman Course, 1948-55; 156125 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - [Student-Faculty Committee on]Freshman Guidance, 1957; 156126 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - [Committee on] Graduate Instruction, 1946-49; 156127 (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
  - Graduate School of Management Committee, 1965-71; 156128 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Student Recruiting Committee, 1965; 156129 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Ad hoc] Health Insurance Committee, 1967-71; 156130 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Health Services Advisory Committee, 1968-72; 156131 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Committee on the] Honor System, 1954, 1980-83; 156132 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - [Committee on the] Honors Program, 1966-67; 156133 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Humanities and Social Science Brochure Committee, 1974; 156134 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Inaugural Committee, 1971; 156135 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [Committee for the] Industrial Administration Program (Proposed), 1964; 156136 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [Committee on] Industrial Engineering, 1967-68; 156520 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - [Faculty Advisory Committee for] Industry and Business Support, 1963-68; 156521 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - [Committee on] Information Center Library/ICSA Space, 156522 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [Committee on the Rice University] Institutional Biosafety, 1978, 1981; 156523 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - [Committee on] Instruction in Applied Mathematics, 1966-67; 156524 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Interdisciplinary Programs Committee, 1973-74; 156525 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Interdisciplinary Research Relevant to Problems of Our Society (IRRPOS), 1970-71; 156526 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - [Committee on] International Business Education, 1976; 156527 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - [Planning Committee for] Joint Center for Urban Studies, 1967; 156528 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - KTRU Radio Committee, 1969-77; 156529 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - [Committee for] Latin American Programs, 1964-66; 156530 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on the] Location of Graduate Lounge, 1970; 156531 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - [Committee for the] Mathematical Sciences Building, 1965-66; 156532 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Metrification, 1975; 156533 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - [Committee on] Minority Admissions, 1968-71; 156534 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Moonlighting, Overtime, and Effective Use of Shops, 1970-71; 156535 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Navy Committee, 1946-49; 156536 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - [Building Committee for the] New Men's College, 1966; 156537 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Permanent Ring Committee, 1962; 156538 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Professional Master's Degree Committee, 1967-70; 156539 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - [Committee on] Professional Personnel, 1965-66; 156540 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - [Committee for] Program in Business Principles, 1973; 156541 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - [Committee on] Publications (an Alumni Committee), 1970-71; 156542 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - [Committee on] Release of Research Equipment, 1969; 156543 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Research Institute Task Force, 1977; 156544 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - [Committee to] Review and Evaluate the Department of Commerce, 1966, 1970-71; 156545 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - [Ad hoc Select Comm. For] Review of Intercollegiate Athletics at Rice, 1975-76; 156546 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - [Ad hoc Committee for] Science Program for Non-Science Students, 1976-77; 156547 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - [Faculty-Student Advisory Committee for] Selection of a President, 1968-70; 156548 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - [Committee on the Rice University] Service Award, 1963-68; 156549 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - [Committee on the] Social Sciences Building, 1968; 156550 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Space Sciences, 1962-63; 156551 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Special Presidential Commission on the Nature of the University, 1970; 156595 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Statistics Courses, 1969, 1981-82; 156596 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Student Center Board, 1970-71; 156597 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Student-Faculty Relations, 1955-56; 156598 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - [Faculty-Student Committee on] Student Housing, 1954-58; 156599 (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - [Ad hoc Committee to] Study Effect of Increased Tuition, 1977; 156600 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - [Committee for the] Study of Possible Graduate Activities in Drama, 1965-67; 156601 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Study of Practices in Admissions, Registration, and Financial Aid, 1969-71; 156602 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - [Committee to] Study the Scholarship Program, 1954-55; 156603 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Summer School Evaluation, 156604 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - [Administrative Committee in] Systems Theory and Applied Mathematics, 1965; 156605 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Related Archival Materials
    See also: [Ad hoc Committee on] Applied Maths. and Systems Research (Box 3)
  - [Committee on] Tenure and Ethics, 1971-76, 1980; 156606 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - [Committee on] Training Program for Administrative, Secretarial & Clerical Personnel, 1978; 156607 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Tuition, 1962; 156608 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - [Ad hoc Committee on] Undergraduate Summer Programs, 1975-79, 1981; 156609 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Water Resource Studies Committee, 1964; 156610 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Series II: Ad Hoc Curriculum Review Committee, 156014
  - Committee Correspondence, 1996; 156015 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Budget Information, July 1996; 156016 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Committee Correspondence, Jan.-May 1997; 156017 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Committee Correspondence, June-Dec. 1997; 156018 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Committee Correspondence, July-Dec. 1998 and undated; 156020 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Committee Correspondence, Jan.-June, 1998; 156019 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Responses, Meeting Minutes, 1996-98; 156021 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Earlier Rice material, 1980s-early 1990s; 156022 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Earlier Rice material, 1994; 156023 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Earlier Rice material, 1995; 156024 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Information, Responses, 1997-98; 156025 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Seminars, 1996-97; 156043 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Languages, 1987-98; 156044 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lists [Departments, Courses, Ways of Knowing], 1997-98; 156045 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Proposal, 1994-98 and undated; 156046 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Proposal, 1997-98; 156047 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Surveys, 1996-97; 156048 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Science, Technology, 1994-97; 156049 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Technology, 1997-98; 156050 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Writing, 1996-98; 156051 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Thresher, Rice News, 1994, 1998; 156052 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Courses, Programs, 1994-98 and undated; 156053 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Rice course inventories, spring 1998; 156054 (Box 14, Folder 2-4)
  - List of other universities from which material collected, 156055 (Box 14, Folder 5)